Guide to the Edith R. Mirrielees Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Edith R. Mirrielees papers
1863-1964
SC1028
Mirrielees, Edith R., (Edith Ronald), 1878-1962.
0.5 Linear feet
Primarily personal correspondence with former students and friends regarding their writings and her life at Stanford. Also includes naturalization and citizenship papers of her father, James Mirrielees, and her own birth certificate. Correspondents include Bernard De Voto, Wallace Stegner and Harry Bush.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Sources varied.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Mirrielees was Professor of English at Stanford 1909-1944, emeritus 1944-1962.
Description of the Collection
Collection primarily contains personal correspondence with former students and friends regarding their writings and her life at Stanford, along with naturalization and citizenship papers of her father, James Mirrielees, and her own birth certificate. Correspondents include Avis De Voto, Bernard De Voto, Mary Stegner, Wallace Stegner, and Harry Bush.
Access Terms
Bush, Harry.; De Voto, Avis; De Voto, Bernard Augustine, 1897-1955; Mirrielees, Edith R., (Edith Ronald), 1878-1962.; Mirrielees, James.; Stanford University. Department of English. Faculty.; Stegner, Mary; Stegner, Wallace Earle, 1909-1993; Authors.; College teachers.; English language --Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, incoming and outgoing, including Catherine Drinker Bowen (Kitty), Mr. Frantz, Mrs. Bernard de Voto (Avis), Mary Stegner, and Wallace Stegner, 1915-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence with Bernard de Voto, 1938-1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, outgoing to Harry Bush (cousin), 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, outgoing to Julie Sloane, 1950-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, outgoing to Jess Treat, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence of Harry Bush re: the death of Mirrielees and the donation of her papers, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, incoming to Dorothy Rich, re Mirrielees' death and Memorial Resolution, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence of Leon Selzer re Mirrielees' death, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Article: "Dear Young Writer," in THE WRITER, 1962 Aug (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Articles - retirement and obituaries, 1944-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous papers, includng Edith Mirrielees' birth certificate and certificate of discharge and naturalization papers of her father James Mirrielees, 1863-1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)